hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says solve for x and it's giving us this
shape right here we have a 75° angle
here we have this segment the same
length as this segment the same length
as this segment and there's a right
angle right here and it wants us to find
the value of x if you want to try it on
your own posit right now because I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 first let's
focus on this right triangle any
triangle can be inscribed in a circle so
let's inscribe it in a circle and for
every inscribed right triangle the
hypoten is the diameter of the circle so
we know that the center is going to lie
on this hypotenuse and since we know
this is congruent to this we know the
center is going to be right there and
each of these are radius of the circle
and we can draw another radius from the
center of the circle to the vertex of
the right angle now I think this is
everything we need to solve the problem
if you want to pause it now cuz I'm
going to actually solve it in 3 2 1 for
the next step if this angle is X this
angle right here will also be X and
these are called vertical angles and
then we don't know how big this angle is
so let's call it y so now if we focus on
this angle right here if the inscribed
angle is y The Arc that it subtends is
always double the inscribed angle so
this Arc from here to here is 2 y de and
then if we focus on this angle the
central angle is always congruent to the
measure of the arc so if this Arc is 2 y
de this angle will be 2 y de next we can
label this angle right here Z degre and
if we focus on this isoceles triangle in
an isoceles triangle you have two sides
congruent and you also have the base
angles congruent so this angle right
here will also be equal to Z de so now
we're ready to do some algebra we can
focus on these three angles right here
we have 2 y + z + 75 is equal to 180 and
then next we can focus on this triangle
right here the sum of the interior
angles of any triangle is 180° we know
that x + y + 75 is equal to 180 and last
let's focus on this right triangle we
know that x + z + 90 will equal 180 now
let's clean these up a little bit for
the first one we can subtract 75 from
both sides and we can do the same thing
for the second one and then for the
third one we can subtract 90 from both
sides 75 - 75 is 0 75 - 75 is 0 and 90 -
90 is 0 and then 180 - 75 is 105 180 -
75 is 105 and 180 - 90 is 90 right now
we have an x a y and a z and we want to
solve for x we're going to do this with
elimination now let's rearrange things a
little bit for this second equation
let's multiply both sides of the
equation by -2 this -2 will distribute
to both of these giving us -2X and -2 Y
and then on the right hand side 105 * -2
is -210 and let's shift that up here now
we can add these two equations together
we can bring down the -2X pos2 y -2 y
will go away and we can bring down the
positive Z and then on this side 105 -
210 is
105 and now we're down to x and z so we
just got to eliminate the Z we're going
to multiply both sides of this bottom
equation by1 the negative 1 will
distribute to give USX and negative Z
and on the right hand side it will be 90
and then we can bring that up here and
add the two equations together -2X - 1X
will be -3x and5 - 90 is-
1995 now to solve for x let's divide
both sides by 3 on the left hand side we
have X and on the right hand side -195 /
-3 is POS 65 so now we found this
unknown angle X is equal to 65 and this
is the answer to our question let's put
a box around it how exciting here's the
next problem I plan on working on if you
guys want to try it out I'll post the
solution as soon as I solve it how
exciting